在本节中，我们将考虑另一个空间图像处理操作
In this section we are going to consider another spatial image processing operation, goes by
数学形态学的相当标题。现在，形态词意味着
the rather confronting title of mathematical morphology. Now the word morphology means
形状，所以这是一种敏感的空间图像处理操作
shape, so this is a type of spatial image processing operation that is sensitive to
形状。输出图像包含与结构元素兼容的形状
shape. The output image contains shapes that are compatible with a structuring element
S.现在，结构元素是一种表示其中像素子集的模式
S. Now the structuring element is a pattern which represents a subset of pixels within
我们希望考虑的输入窗口。一个例子就是说清楚：我们有一个
the input window that we wish to consider. An example will make that clear: we have a
这里设计的例子，简单的二进制场景，黑色像素和包含的白色像素
contrived example here, simple binary scene, black pixels and white pixels that contain
不同大小的正方形和矩形。与之前的动画一样，我们看到了输入
squares and rectangles of different sizes. As in previous animations, we see the input
此处显示的窗口以红色从左到右，从上到下穿过图像。什么
window shown here in red marching across the image left to right and top to bottom. What
在这种情况下不同的是，只有下面的所有像素输出才为真
is different in this case is that the output is only true if all of the pixels underneath
红色的窗口是真的。到目前为止还没有。在一瞬间，我们将看到......这一个
the red window are true. So far none have been. In a moment we will see… this one
特殊情况现在......输出图像包含一个像素。这就是所有的
particular case now… where the output image contains one pixel. That is where all of the
红色行进窗口下面的像素都已设置。你会注意到大部分
pixels underneath the red marching window were all set. You will notice that most of
输入图像中的形状消失了，矩形全部消失了，
the shapes that were in the input image have disappeared, the rectangles have all disappeared,
小广场消失了;唯一保留的形状是大广场。
the little square has disappeared; the only shape that was retained was the big square.
请注意，大方块的形状与红色行进窗口的形状相同。我们只说
Note that the big square was the same shape as the red marching window. We say that only
保留与结构元素兼容的形状-3x3平方。
shapes that are compatible with the structuring element — a 3 x 3 square — are retained.
这个操作也被称为侵蚀，因为这里发生的是我们的
This operation is also referred to as erosion, because what has happened here is that our
3x3平方，即使它是兼容的，已被侵蚀......像素已经
3 x 3 square, even though it is compatible, has been eroded away … pixels have been
咀嚼它的边缘，直到只剩下中心像素。通常会调用此操作
chewed off its edges until only the centre pixel is left. This operation is often called
腐蚀和这个功能可以使用工具箱函数ierode计算;首先
erosion and this function can be computed using the tool box function ierode; the first
参数是图像，第二个参数是结构元素。在这种情况下
argument is the image and the second argument is the structuring element. In this case it
是一个包含3×3矩阵的矩阵。所以我们可以执行逆向操作，
is a 3 x 3 matrix containing ones. So we can perform the converse operation,
这被称为扩张，我们再次在动画中展示这一点。这是3x3游行
which is called dilation, and again we show this in animation. Here is the 3 x 3 marching
窗口，但现在用于扩张，如果红色正方形下面有任何像素，则输出为真
window, but now for dilation, the output is true if any pixel underneath the red square
是真的。到目前为止还没有。现在我们看到有一堆像素正在运行
is true. So far none have been. Now we see that there are a bunch of pixels are going
被设置为红色窗口越过它们并遇到一个像素。
to be set as the red window marches across them and encounters a one pixel.
这个操作被称为扩张，这显然是因为它已经扩张了一个像素
This operation is called dilation for the obvious reason that it has taken a single pixel, dilated
把它长成3x3的形状;事实上，它恢复到原来的形状。
it, grown it into a 3 x 3 shape; in fact, it is back to the shape that it was originally.
这个功能，这个扩张功能，可以使用工具箱功能idilate计算;
This function, this dilation function, can be computed using tool box function idilate;
第一个参数是输入图像，第二个参数是结构元素。
the first argument is the input image and the second argument is the structuring element.
所以这是我们拥有的原始图像，然后我们将其侵蚀为单个像素
So this was the original image that we had and we eroded it to a single pixel and then
我们扩大它，使单个像素成为3x3像素的块。所以你可以看到什么
we dilated it so that the single pixel became a block of 3 x 3 pixels. So you can see what
在这里发生过，我们拍摄了原始图像，我们已经侵蚀了它，扩张了它
has happened here, we have taken an original image, we have eroded it, dilated it and the
只有3x3方形的形状才能完全成型。矩形有
only shape that made it all the way through was the 3 x 3 square. The rectangles have
消失了，小方块消失了，这是因为只有形状
disappeared and the little square has disappeared and that is because only the shapes that are
与结构元素兼容已得到维护。现在这个操作，这个
compatible with the structuring element have been maintained. Now this operation, this
侵蚀随后扩张的序列通常被称为开放。只有兼容
sequence of erosion followed by dilation, is often called opening. Only the compatible
形状仍然存在，我们可以使用函数iopen在工具箱中执行此操作。
shapes have remained and we can do this in the tool box using the function iopen.
让我们尝试以相反的顺序做事。
Let’s try doing things in the opposite order.
让我们先扩张然后腐蚀，所以在扩张步骤中我们可以动画这个，然后
Let’s dilate first and then erode, so in the dilation step we can animate this, and
对于扩张输出，如果行进窗口下方的任何像素为真，则像素为真
for dilation output pixels are true if any pixel underneath the marching window is true
正如我们所期望的那样，扩张形状会变得更大。但另一个有趣的
and as we would expect for dilation the shape is going to get bigger. But another interesting
这种扩张步骤的好处是形状内的孔将被填充
benefit of this dilation step is that holes within the shape are going to be filled in
它已经变得更大，其中的洞已被关闭。
and it has got bigger and holes within it have been closed up.
现在我们有扩张的图像，现在我们可以侵蚀它。因此侵蚀将被扼杀
Now we have the dilated image, now we can erode it. So erosion is going to chew off
在这个特定物体外面的一个像素的条带;它会
a strip of one pixels all around the outside of this particular object; it is going to
将其恢复到原始大小和形状。
restore it to something like its original size and shape.
现在让我们看一下原始图像。然后它的扩张版本。然后是它的侵蚀版本。
Now let’s look at the original image. Then its dilated version. And then its eroded version.
我们可以看到我们有一些看起来像原始形状的东西，除了内部的洞
And we can see we have something that looks like the original shape, except the hole within
它已被填写。此操作称为关闭操作。它倾向于关闭那些
it has been filled in. This operation is called a closing operation. It tends to close those
物体内的洞。所以任何小于结构元素大小的洞-哪个
holes within an object. So any hole that is smaller than the size of the structuring element — which
是一个3x3像素的块-将被填充。这个关闭操作可以使用
is a 3 x 3 pixel block — will be filled in. This closing operation can be computed using
工具箱功能iclose。所以这给我们带来了兼容性的概念
the tool box function iclose. So this brings us to the notion of compatibility between
结构元素和形状。所以这里的结构元素是红色正方形
a structuring element and a shape. So here a structuring element is a red square and
我打算用大方块和薄矩形来测试它。
I am going to test it against a large square and a thin rectangle.
首先，我们将测试大型广场，基本上它是说如果
So first of all we are going to test the large square and basically it is saying that if
我可以将结构元素放入该形状中，它将在侵蚀操作中存活
I can fit the structuring element within that shape it will survive in an erosion operation
或打开操作，但对于高大的薄矩形，其中没有任何地方
or an opening operation, but for the tall thin rectangle there is nowhere within that
结构元素适合的形状。因此，这种形状将无法生存
shape that the structuring element will fit. So this shape will not survive, it will be
在侵蚀步骤中消除。相反，如果我的结构元素是
eliminated in the erosion step. Conversely, if my structuring element is a
高瘦的矩形我们会发现实际上没有这个高大的薄矩形
tall thin rectangle we will find that there is actually nowhere that this tall thin rectangle
可以放在大广场内。所以如果我的结构元素是一个高大的薄矩形，
can fit inside the large square. So if my structuring element is a tall thin rectangle,
这个广场将消失。然而，那个高大的薄矩形会存活，所以形状
this square will disappear. However, that tall thin rectangle will survive, so the shape
结构元素的控制将控制将保留在输出图像中的形状;
of the structuring element controls the shapes that will be retained in the output image;
它是一个对形状敏感的过滤器。
it is a filter that is sensitive to shape.